Shuhel Ahmed

Sylhet, Bangladesh Email: shuhel@ymail.com

Github: http://github.com/ahmedshuhel

Summary

- Full-stack software engineer offering 10+ years of experience working in a variety of environments with a breadth of programs and technologies.
- Extensive experience in Agile Development, Test-Driven Development, Domain-Driven Design, Object-Oriented Design, Service Oriented Architecture.
- Experience in building high traffic web applications and APIs, large-scale data processing systems on the AWS Platform.
- Strong exposure to infrastructure orchestration tools (Ansible, Docker), and Linux as a programming environment.
- Proven track record in providing technical leadership.

Key areas

Enterprise Applications, Agile, Databases (SQL/NoSQL), JavaScript, Test-driven development (TDD/BDD), SPA, Domain Driven Design, CQRS, Event Sourcing, Design Patterns. REST, SOA, MVVM, MVP, MVC, User Experience.

Technology Stack

Client Side: JavaScript, React, Aurelia, DurandalJS, AngularJS, Winforms, WPF.

Server Side: Python, .NET, Node.

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB

UI Prototyping: Axure RP

Operating System: Windows, Linux

Programming Language

Language	Level	Known	since
Python	Professional		2013
JavaScript	Professional		2007
C#	Professional		2005
Typescript Intermediate			2014

Experience

2016-Present Tech Lead & Enginnering Manager NewsCred Inc.

- Led effort in re-writing and improving core product area in Content Marketing Platform in ReactJS from AngularJS.
- Developed NewsCred for Sales, an ABCM system, that helps the Sales Department engage with Leads and Opportunities via content.

- Developed an internal tool for tracking original content budgets, improving the productivity of the Editorial team by more than 70%
- Developed tools to measure Content Marketing maturity of customers, improving efficiency in deployment and program adoption.
- Modeled an automated data pipeline which aggregates data from various sources to AWS Redshift and then created data visualization to understand the trend, usage pattern, etc.
- Wrote services and APIs on AWS EC2 using Django REST Framework, Flask, NodeJS, MySQL, and Elasticsearch, automated infrastructure management using Ansible, built CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins.
- Lead and guide engineering teams to design scalable systems and cooperate with the Product Manager to plan and schedule.
- Managing 4 software engineers as an engineering manager and assisting them to grow in the organization.
- Line manage a group of talented software engineers, guide them to perform on their highest potential and achieve their career goal by providing regular feedback and conducting one on ones.

2012–2016 Senior Software Engineer C&E Software Solutions

- Developed an ERP solution for one of the largest government organizations with over 150000 users. The system manages 820 units located across the country and over 250000 people. The solution consists of several modules like HRM, Accounting, Training, Result Processing, Stock & Inventory, Ration Management, POL Management, Point of Sale, etc.
- Led the development effort of the company's flagship product, Hospital ERP. This complex system consists several sub-modules including OPD, IPD, Nursing Station, Admission, Emergency, OT, Day Care Center, Diagnostic Center, Follow Up and Prescription, MRD, MIS, and Accounting, Billing, Payroll, HRM, etc.
- Implemented a visual query builder and a search platform that operates on a highly denormalized data repository containing a huge volume of data.
- Decomposed an existing monolithic system into a microservice architecture to achieve tarted performance improvement.
- Wrote scaffolders in PowerShell and a helper framework that cut down the development time from 6/7 days to 5/6 hours for developers.
- Wrote/implemented an algorithm in C# to arrange/sort c# DTO types/objects in terms of dependency during runtime that facilitated reliable change detection and updating/patching.
- Led a team of 5 engineers and provided training on TDD/BDD, CI/CD and frameworks like AngularJS, Angular Material, ASP.NET MVC, etc.
- Led effort in requirement gathering and analysis by collaborating with domain experts and stakeholders. Created high fidelity mock-ups with Auxre RP to understand and deliver the desired user experience.
- Implemented OpenID Connect based authentication/authorization with IdentityServer for single sign-on across multiple apps.
- Implemented a CI/CD pipeline with TeamCity. Providing continuous integration and unit testing on .NET based projects which are used in the company's core product.

Software Developer 2010 - 2012 PosCube(Independent Developer)

- Designed and developed a restaurant management system (RMS) and integrated online order processing system that is being used by over 150 UK restaurants. The system is designed and optimized for POS hardware.
- Developed and evolved a touch-based UI with WinForms that works with POS terminal by carefully observing usage patterns achieving a level of user-friendliness that sets us apart.
- Developed an MVC framework for WinForms with SPA like experience and used in the application.
- Integrated with hardware like POS printer, Label Printer, Caller Id via direct interfacing COM, USB, and serial ports interfacing as well as supporting OPOS standards via POS.NET.
- Implemented a windows installer for the application with WIX that also creates the backend database and let users configure the system during installation.
- Designed and developed a tablet-based companion application to take dine-in orders.
- Developed an online ordering system for restaurants.

Software Engineer 2008 – 2010 C&E Software Solutions Ltd

- Wrote C# and WinForms applications that record sales, monitor inventory, keep customer ledger, and bill customer for a drinking water plant and distribution company.
- Wrote a utility billing software for supermarket/shopping centers using C#, .NET, and Winforms.

Education

Metropolitan University - Sylhet, Bangladesh, 2008 B.Sc., Computer Science & Engineering

Open Source

- Core team member of Aurelia Framework
- Contributed to <u>Aurelia (https://github.com/aurelia/framework)</u>, <u>JSPM</u> (https://github.com/jspm/jspm-cli), SystemJS Builder, Fluent Migrator, Humanizer, etc.

Hobbies and Interests

- Contributing to open-source projects.
- Reading code on Github, reading/learning the history and evolution of programming languages.
- Movies and Music.